Do you really think
you could get this far by yourself?
No one in the world besides me
can cross that line and come in here.
Do you know what would happen
if this machine were not scanning my iris?
I suppose the response would be dramatic.
Correct.
If it hadn't correctly detected my iris
within ten seconds,
methane gas would pour in
through all those nozzles,
and then…
A spark.
Exactly. All this
would become a great ring of fire.
Like the third ring
in the seventh circle of Dante's hell.
So, either a Marvel character shows up,
a fireproof one with my eyes,
or no one…
No one could get to this door.
Look at this masterpiece.
No handles,
no locks,
no hydraulic keys.
Mysteriously shut.
What do you think?
Brilliant.
Keila!
Keila, are you there?
What?
I was right.
- I was right!
- About what, Damián?
He has a barbecue down there.
It's a trap for roasting elephants.
Getting in there is completely impossible.
He's a genius.
A fricking master, he's…
Excuse me. The wine.
- Damián.
- Everything's stained now.
It's okay.
The painting will leave Kraków
in a suitcase at 8:15 a.m.
on a normal flight.
It'll be protected with wood,
bulletproof glass, a seal.
Like all the artwork loaned by the…
Thank you. …Czartoryski.
We'll come back to this later.
Time of arrival.
Time…
12:30 p.m. at Seville's airport.
There it'll be picked up
by a private security company,
specialized in transporting art.
I got it here.
And, like any truck transporting
a treasure, it'll be armored.
The company is called Blindesart,
and these are their trucks.
A veritable moving fortress,
and here begin our problems.
No, there we ambush the truck.
And shoot the glass point-blank like this.
We get the guards out,
and in 12 seconds, you have the box open.
Very good idea,
but there are some issues to bear in mind.
First, the glass is bulletproof.
Second, unlike other armored money trucks,
the guards in this one don't have keys.
- They don't?
- No. There is no key.
They have a combination,
and the guards don't know it, for safety.
And if we use the moving truck technique?
- Which one's that?
- You don't know it?
- From Fast & Furious.
- Fast & Furious?
Yes, kidnap a truck,
and stick it into a bigger truck.
Good idea,
but we'd have to be behind the wheel.
Well, don't you get picky now.
After all, it's a fake plan
to fool the duke.
No, Candela.
The plan needs to be perfect and real
to shake that smug fool.
And, the greater the difficulties,
the more brilliant the plan.
Damn.
You talk a pretty game. You're so smart.
I'll end up feeling sad
we're not stealing that lady.
- Why?
- Because it irritates me.
Our first robbery together
as a couple, and it's fake.
And the plan is going to be so pretty.
Hey, look. Thieves on duty again, huh?
I'm going to Pepe's tavern for some eggs.
I'm starving.
You have your chit-chat with the band.
Bye.
- Hello.
- I couldn't call before.
You won't believe what happened.
We left port escorted by the marine guard.
As the boat was about to leave, diplomats
and important people started to arrive
to give their respects
to the illustrious passengers.
You know what that means.
No one's searching that pallet.
Precisely.
Those passengers
are the perfect alibi to avoid suspicion.
- Have you found the rice?
- I searched everywhere, but no luck.
Not a trace.
There must be some kind of secret hold.
A hidden area.
They're stowing the goods somewhere.
I measured the height of two levels.
That of the holds and engine room
and the cabins level.
And it turns out
there's a 65-cm gap between them.
You know what that means?
That there's a hidden cavity
between those levels.
I'll look into it.
It must be a technical space for pipes.
For AC or something like that.
It could also be a false floor
to hide contraband.
Only one way to find out.
You're not thinking
of making a hole in your cabin.
- Right?
- Why not?
Because!
That's your problem in life.
You do the opposite
of what you have to do.
When people ask you to go, you don't.
When they tell you to stay, you run away.
When you're unfaithful to your lover,
you humiliate him and blame him.
You're your worst enemy.
That's your opinion.
I only hope you realize I'm right
before it's too late.
You'll crawl into a hole
in the middle of the ocean.
With no escape route.
You're assuming I'll be caught.
What if I make it?
Don't do it! That's an order!
Fine.
I love swans.
I can't stop smiling
since I saw you in your white shirt.
Dinner is at 8:00, on your boat.
I haven't been on a date since I was 15.
Just the thought
sends shivers down my spine.
I'm so flustered…
I'll lose my babysitter.
Please, don't think me a duck.
Like you, I have the soul of a swan.
The danger is exciting.
Yes, what is it?
Damián, it's Roi.
Get out.
Get out!
- What are you looking at?
- I saw your books.
What books?
The ones on divination and palm reading.
Oh, that?
Yeah. My grandma used to read palms.
So did my mother, and so do I.
No. I only read for people I don't know.
No.
Come on.
I'm asking as a personal favor.
I could use a look into the future
at this moment in my life, please.
Please.
Don't get nervous.
Hey, look. You have the line of success.
Not many people have it, mind you.
Only those who are lucky.
Yours is very pronounced.
Look, there it is.
Right.
- And love?
- Oh.
Love?
Your love line is very braided.
What does that mean?
That you have many, many stories,
and very intense.
That's the line of someone
who loves for real.
But here things get…
Look, here it's very intense and red.
This is a great love.
Andalusian, I'd say.
A very good-looking girl.
A bit of a thief
and an occasional pyromaniac.
Something nice
is going to happen with her.
What?
I only read the future.
I don't dictate it.
But it's very beautiful.
Will I have to wait long?
Are you in a hurry?
More than a hurry. I'm dying to live it.
Tell me everything.
Well, I have good news and bad news.
Shall we start with the bad?
The bad news is
you'll get seriously ill.
And the good news?
That you won't die from that.
Thieves on duty.
Take your band's calls. I'm off
to pick watermelons with my father.
- Hello.
- All four of us are on speakerphone.
- Can you talk?
- Go ahead.
Down there, we have an igloo-shaped
titanium armored vault
in a hallway that needs to ID
the duke's iris in 10 seconds
or it turns into a ring of fire.
The hallway houses deposits
of flammable methane gas.
Exotic.
Did you work out all that megalomaniac
macabre fantasy with the GPR?
No. I saw it with my own eyes.
Last night, strolling around the palace,
I found the duke,
who couldn't sleep either.
We had some wine,
went down to the stables…
The stables?
Late at night?
Yes, what are you thinking?
Nothing. But you just kicked me
out of your room screaming, on all fours.
It seemed like you weren't alone.
You said he took you down to the stables,
and I connected the dots.
What about the bodyguard?
I see a weird relationship there.
Maybe he's also taken
for a roll in the hay.
To the stables, not the hay.
It was a night of male bonding.
Of friendship.
We hugged a horse.
It's his system to reduce stress levels.
Then we talked about life.
We sang a Mexican corrido.
Great. And then?
He took me to the crypt.
He showed me everything.
The first door is opened
with an alphanumeric code, as we thought,
but as soon as you're
in the circular hallway,
if the system does not ID the duke's iris…
you're torched.
It's an inviolable masterwork.
The man is a genius.
We won't be able to steal his money.
Of course we will.
There's always a way.
Oh, yeah? What?
Take his eyeballs so we can scan them?
Maybe we won't have
to gouge anyone's eyeballs out.
We have enough data. We can
make calculations and find other ways.
Exactly.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
The oxygen.
It's a hypothesis,
but with the data we have,
we can calculate the volume of oxygen
in the hallway and combustion time.
And could you now give us
the version for the general public?
Once the fire's consumed all the oxygen
in the hallway, it will die out.
Then we'll move to the next phase.
Opening the igloo's door.
Without oxygen in the air?
We can take oxygen tanks.
And fireproof suits to withstand the fire.
For the love of God, those only work
for a short period of time.
Mere seconds.
Any miscalculation could be fatal.
We'll round up for safety.
And how will you open the titanium door?
Without oxygen,
you can't ignite a thermal lance,
so what will you do?
What's gotten into you, Damián?
You don't want to do it?
It's not that I don't want to.
I'm assessing the risk.
Don't start lying to me now.
You're involved like a schoolboy
about to bed the duchess.
With messages all day
and clandestine rendezvous,
while you become
her husband's best friend.
I know you.
You're beginning to feel empathy.
Maybe even thinking
this robbery is a betrayal, am I wrong?
What was your motto?
"A heist is surgery and cold heads."
Do you think
you're behaving like a professional?
I guess not.
Whatever must be done down there,
we'll solve with science.
As we've always done.
Check, please.
This should cover it.
- Camille.
- Hi.
I see you still remember my name.
I haven't forgotten yours.
I have a surprise for you at my hotel.
- Come with me.
- No.
I can't go right now.
Why don't we talk here?
It's not an invitation.
It's an order.
Shall we?
I calculated the oxygen volume
in the vault's hallway.
It's 79.68 cubic meters.
Estimating a methane inflow
of 0.2 cubic meters per second,
through the nozzles,
the ball of fire shouldn't take
more than 45 seconds
to consume all the oxygen in there.
That's the time the suit needs to resist?
That's right.
At ignition
and for some tenths of a second,
combustion temperature will reach 1,963ºC.
Then it will stabilize
between 400 and 600 degrees.
There are materials
that resist those temperatures.
Fibers like Nomex,
or aluminized suits
like firefighters wear.
How will we know if the suit works?
We can test it.
How?
With a flamethrower.
You think this is a escape room, Roi?
First demolition, now what? Conflagration?
It's the adrenaline boost I need.
I'm not scared.
We need someone with a cool head
in there, not a kamikaze.
- Bruce will go.
- What?
You have a volunteer and pick me?
I don't want to go.
It's technically possible.
We'll be at 600 degrees in that hole.
I'm not barbecue meat.
I'm not arguing. You'll both go.
Figure out where we can source
the fireproof suits.
And scram. I have things to do.
It's here.
You're as beautiful as always.
Although you seem different.
Must be the gun.
Do you see me as different?
Really?
Maybe.
I went through some life changes.
An ex-husband with a secret child
ended up in jail.
And a slippery lover
stood me up in Singapore.
Why didn't you go?
I got stuck in Colombia's Coffee Axis
when a volcano erupted.
They cancelled all flights.
What are you doing?
Easy.
All the country's roads
were jammed for days.
It was impossible to get out.
So, desperate,
I called the Blue Moon in Singapore.
I was hopeful again,
because a waiter called Ralph
agreed to help me.
Help you how?
I bought a ticket to Argentina.
I asked him to print it and put it
in a red envelope with my phone number,
and to write your name on it
and give it to you.
I thought it romantic to meet
in another continent because of a volcano
because, after all,
our relationship was like a volcano.
I never got that envelope.
I probably misread the signals
and was too generous with that guy, Ralph.
Because I paid for the favor in advance.
When the time for our date came
and you didn't call, I called him again.
Blue Moon.
Still, I called again.
But I must confess I was irritated
and didn't conduct myself as a gentleman.
I never heard again from Ralph,
the 20,000 euros I sent him,
or what became of the envelope.
Or, of course, from you.
We were both left waiting that same night.
On different continents.
But now we're here.
Together.
The fire of a volcano
couldn't keep us apart.
Will you force me
to steal a kiss at gunpoint?
Point that at my head as much as you want,
but you won't get that kiss.
Our moment's gone.
I'm in love with someone else now.
I know.
Yes, I saw her.
That Andalusian woman, so…
So spirited. Yes.
But there was someone
when you came into my life too.
And still, I let you get in that taxi
and come with me to that concert.
I gave you the chance
to completely change my world.
And now you owe me the same chance.
And that's why I came.
One moment.
Damián's so tense.
Just like us.
What do you mean?
Did you notice what Berlin said?
He's in a triangle
with the duke and the duchess.
- Can I have your phone?
- Sure.
Can you unlock it?
I'm calling this guy.
What? Not over the phone.
Let's solve this like adults.
It's the 21st century, right?
Do you still have him under Mom?
Yes.
Hi, Keila.
No, it's Bruce, her boyfriend.
I hope you didn't steal her phone
to snoop.
No. Keila's here with me. Wait.
- Say hi.
- Hi, Claudio.
Is everything all right?
- Yes, everything's fine.
- It's all good, Claudio.
We wanted to invite you to dinner.
- What do you think?
- Hey.
You're not setting this up
to give me a beating, right?
No, on the contrary.
We can get margaritas at a Mexican place,
talk about life, have fun…
Go with the flow.
We'll drop you a pin, okay?
Tomorrow or the day after. Bye.
I swear I'm dying to know
how far you'll take this lover business…
Genoveva. Sorry, I didn't recognize you.
Blonde suits you.
A wig, to throw Samuel off my scent.
I went into Zara through a door,
put on the wig, and walked out another.
Like a double agent.
Quite the adrenaline rush.
Come in, please.
How Bohemian, living on a boat.
Well…
I was so pleased
to see you wear that white shirt.
Well, actually, I had no choice.
You had an advantage.
The dress code forced me.
You're saying you were forced to be here?
No.
Here's what we agreed on for the date.
Your 500,000.
In photocopies.
You're more cunning than me.
Although there's something
I still can't figure out.
If you already have your money
and it seems I forced you to meet me here,
why the nice dinner?
With candles and flowers.
What are you up to?
Huh?
What are you doing?
Does it amuse you to see me
resort to disguises to see you?
- No, it's not that.
- No? What is it, then?
Why go this far?
Toying with a married woman excites you?
No. I'm not toying. I'm in love with you.
I avoid you by day,
fantasize with your portrait by night,
keep your notes…
I live in torment,
dreaming of you at all hours.
I've dreamt of you too.
We were on a boat like this.
Do you want me to tell you
what happened now?
Nothing will happen.
At first, I rejected you
because I am your husband's partner.
Now I have two more reasons.
The first one is…
Well, the duke and I
are becoming friends and…
He's a great guy. You know that.
And the second?
My marriage broke up over an infidelity.
I know how devastating that is
to a person's life.
I don't feel…
capable of doing that to anyone.
You speak…
of infidelity, betrayal,
of horrible things
that cast a shadow
over this wonderful moment.
I guess…
I guess it's not a betrayal…
for me to graze your hand.
No.
I guess not.
And I guess
it's not a sin
to grab your arm.
I guess not.
And I think…
I think it's also
not a sin
to breathe in your scent.
I guess not.
I think it's not a sin either
for us to dance to your favorite song.
I guess not.
Let me propose something.
Let's run away.
Wait until it's all over,
and I promise you,
one minute after the theft,
after I lose sight of your husband,
we'll go to whichever continent you want,
with the life you want
and the soundtrack you want.
Thank you for the proposal.
I'll let you know my decision.
What's this, Camille?
A café au lait.
Don't you remember?
That's how it all started.
At that bar counter.
With the smell
of freshly-baked croissants.
Paris…
on your lips.
Are you starting to remember?
You told me you had heard me sing a song
the night before.
I took off these panties for you
at that restaurant.
They're yours.
You can't possibly
not remember what we were.
What we could do together.
It's not over.
I'm sure all we felt is here.
Somewhere in your memory.
I was just talking about you.
Shut up, please.
What's your name?
Camille. Pleased to meet you.
Candela.
She's the woman
I fell in love with in Paris.
Before I met you.
If you were with her in Paris,
why get involved with me?
Because I wasn't with her anymore.
Not when I met you, nor two months before,
when I couldn't meet her
at the Blue Moon in Singapore.
I never heard from him again.
Love stories end
when one of the two breaks up.
In our case, neither of us did.
Camille.
Ours was a relationship without phones,
of waiting for the other
on different continents.
It fell apart.
I love you like crazy.
Like never before.
But we don't belong together.
And it's not because of her.
I'm sure she's wonderful.
We have different lives. I've never been
to the Blue Moon in Singapore.
I don't even know what that is.
But that's your thing.
You're about what's shiny,
elegant, sophisticated.
I'm more about, well…
meeting my friends
at the fountain in the square,
eating fried eggs with my hands,
picking watermelons
with my father on Fridays…
I'm more about the little things.
My life's full of little things.
I love it,
because it's the only one I have.
But you have 50,
and in all 50, there's someone
who's chilling champagne for you.
Of those 50 lives,
I choose this one to be with you.
This is the one that fascinates me.
We do love each other, you and I.
You know what?
We would have loved each other forever.
But it can't be.
Because this has an expiration date,
and I'd rather set it myself today.
And if you respect me even a little,
I ask you to please never look for me.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Camille.
We'll take two pistols each
with two clips.
Things can get complicated.
We'll be on the street.
There can be as few as eight.
Four in each vehicle.
The fireproof suits will be in the back.
The sooner you're out, the better. Got it?
Yes. We'll go to the meeting point.
When you have the suits, call me.
I have things to do.
I'll stay.
I'll try to find out
how the armored igloo opens.
I want a clean operation.
Fast. Leave no trace.
Now!
We have a casualty.
Pull.
What are you doing here?
I told you not to look for me.
Is this how you show me respect?
No, not another step.
She told you to leave.
I'll leave as soon as you hear me out.
I swear.
Hey, let's go.
Leave, you bastard.
We saw you with the French woman.
Nothing happened with Camille.
If anything, what happened
at that hotel is that you
saw a way out to run away from me.
- I don't want to talk to you.
- No, Candela.
If you had thought I was being unfaithful,
you would have set me alight yourself
with a can of gas.
You got stage fright.
And you hold on to a bottle of champagne
to say your life is not mine,
but what you really fear is loving.
Loving me so much.
- But you know what?
- What?
I have good news.
I love you just as much.
Or more. Look.
It says so here, right?
You told me yourself.
But there's more here
that maybe you misread.
You think I don't fit in your life.
That's why…
That's why I'll say it loud and clear
for all to hear.
For me, it's an honor…
An honor to come to this field
to pick watermelons
or whatever with your family.
Leave right now, or you leave in a box.
I'll count to three.
- One!
- Dad, please!
Two!
I won't leave, but I won't allow
this conversation to turn into a tragedy.
Simón, put the guns down.
My name's not Simón.
My name is Andrés de Fonollosa.
I usually live
in Madrid's Las Letras district,
above a café called Buenos Aires.
I have a son called Rafael
from an early marriage,
and I am a thief.
And my only thought
since you left that hotel is
how to prove to you
that I'm as madly in love as you.
I’m heading straight toward you, my love.
And that you can definitely
have faith in me.
And, well, the only way
I can think of doing it is…
this.
Could you look
into the pocket of my jacket, please?
And this is the time
when you have to say yes
or no.
Yes, I do.
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy